Drew Herron

✓ dherron@mailbox.org

J (503) 828-8880

Portland, OR

Website

in LinkedIn

GitHub

SUMMARY

Recent master's graduate in computer science with 6+ years of experience in data analytics, data quality, business intelligence, and AI/ML. Strong background in natural language processing, linguistics, data engineering, and cybersecurity. Seeking roles in AI development or applied machine learning; open to relocation and remote work.

EXPERIENCE

Data Project Assistant

07/2019 - 09/2021

Energy Trust of Oregon Portland, OR

- Led data cleanup projects including merging duplicates, updating classifications, and reorganizing hierarchies
- Developed and maintained Power BI reports for tracking data quality, year-end QC, and database health
- Created SQL queries and R programs to analyze and deduplicate data across CRM and database systems
- Collaborated with DBAs to improve database structure and establish business rules for CRM entity classification
- Wrote technical documentation for data merging procedures and contributed code snippets for SQL, R, and DAX

Business Intelligence Developer

09/2016 - 01/2019

WE Communications

Portland, OR

- Helped plan data collection strategies to measure press coverage and public relations impact
- Extracted, manipulated and transformed data using a variety of BI methods
- Conducted analysis of data using such tools as Excel, Power BI, SQL and Python
- Responsible for the creation of visualizations/infographics to convey data clearly and succinctly
- Discovered actionable insights from data trends and drafted detailed reports for clients

Cryptologic Linguist
United States Air Force

12/2008 - 12/2013

Clearance: TS/SCI

- Developed and implemented new methods for tracking productivity and collection data
- Led a team of 30+ translators providing support to US forces deployed abroad
- Facilitated collaboration between multiple teams and organizations
- Trained and qualified new employees in intelligence processing methods
- Maintained DLPT level 3/3 proficiency in both Arabic and German

EDUCATION

M.S. Computer Science 09/2021 – 12/2024

Portland State University

Portland, OR

- Concentration: Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning
- GPA: 4.0; Honor Society of Phi Kappa Phi

Full Stack BootcampPDX Code Guild
Portland, OR

B.A. International Studies

09/2001 - 06/2005

University of Oregon

Eugene, OR

Skills

- Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, Lisp, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Libraries & Tools: Git, Docker, Django, NLTK, PyTorch, TensorFlow, pandas, NumPy, scikit-learn, LangChain
- Data Engineering: Database Design, Query Optimization, ETL, Data Quality, Cloud Infrastructure, GCP, AWS
- AI & ML: LLMs, NLP, Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Sentiment Analysis, Vector Search, Agentic AI, RAG
- Languages: English (Native), German, Arabic, Chinese, learning Portuguese